He was a man of honor in a war without any.
Lion of the Desert is a history, war, drama film directed by Moustapha Akkad.
This movie tells the story of Omar Mukhtar, an Arab Muslim rebel who fought against
the Italian conquest of Libya during the second Italo-Senussi War.
It gives western viewers a glimpse into this little-known region and chapter of history, and
exposes the savage means by which the conquering army attempted to subdue the natives.
Omar Mukhtar, played by Anthony Quinn.
Benito Mussolini, played by Rod Steiger.
Gen. Rodolfo Graziani, played by Oliver Reed.
Mabrouka, played by Irene Papas.
Colonel Diodiece, played by Raf Vallone.
Sharif El Gariani, played by John Gielgud.
Lion of the Desert (alternative titles: Omar Mukhtar and Omar Mukhtar: Lion of the Desert) is a 1981 American-Libyan-British epic historical war film about the Second Italo-Senussi War, starring Anthony
Quinn as Libyan tribal leader Omar Mukhtar, a Bedouin leader fighting the Regio Esercito (Royal Italian Army), and Oliver Reed as Italian General Rodolfo Graziani, who defeated Mukhtar.
It was directed by Syrian-American director Moustapha Akkad.
Released in May 1981, the film has received positive reviews from critics, but performed poorly at the box
office, gaining revenues of US$1.5 million worldwide despite having a $35 million budget.
The film was banned in Italy in 1982 and was only shown on pay TV in 2009.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare,
libya, africa, resistance, world war ii.
The tone is emotional.